Finding Aid for Ann Arbor (Mich.) Planning Consultants Reports, 1951-1993
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor (Mich.) Planning Consultants Reports 1951-1993
Ann Arbor (Mich.). Planning Commission.
3 linear feet
95114 Aa 2
Reports and studies produced for the Ann Arbor Planning Commission on a variety of topics including transportation, housing, downtown and neighborhood development, waste water control, and the city's planning process.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The publications were acquired from the Planning Commission and a number of other donors.
The record group is open without restriction.
Reports and studies produced for the Ann Arbor Planning Commission on a variety of topics including transportation, housing, downtown and neighborhood development, waste water control, and the city's planning process. The reports were prepared by architectural and engineering firms working as consultants to the Planning Commission. The reports are arranged alphabetically by author.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Economic conditions.; City planning--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Transportation--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Planning.
Contributors:
Ahern, Richard D.; Barnes, Douglas.; Byrd, David R.; Dykema, James.; Griffin, Denise.; Hoffman, L. Wallace.; Johnson, William J.; Palmer, John S.; Pelz, Donald Campbell, 1921-; Quinn, Robert P.; Reid, Lloyd B.; Sullivan, Carol.; Zeidman, Fred.; Alan M. Voorhees & Associates.; Ann Arbor Municipal Airport Advisory Committee.; Ann Arbor Tomorrow.; Atwell-Hicks.; Ayres, Lewis, Norris, and May.; Barton-Aschman Associates.; Beckett Raeder Rankin Inc.; BRH Mobility Services Company.; Brewer Engineering.; Colvin-Robinson Associates.; Ann Arbor (Mich.). Community Planning and Management.; Community Systems Foundation.; Economics Research Associates.; Eisenhower Community Council.; Ford Motor Company. Transportation Research and Planning Office.; Harland Bartholomew & Associates.; Hellmuth, Obata & Kassabaum.; Herrmann Holman Meneghini Overhiser.; Hubbell, Roth and Clark.; Johnson & Anderson.; Johnson, Johnson & Roy.; Jones & Henry Engineers Limited.; McNamee, Porter, and Seeley.; Metro Engineers, Inc.; Preservation Urban Design Incorporated.; Ralph M. Parsons Company.; Reid and Cool (Firm); Residents Against Packard Platt Plaza.; Sanders & Thomas.; Schimpeler-Corradino Associates.; Technical Network Inc.; TransPlan, Inc.; W.C. Gilman & Co.; Wayne C. Johnson & Associates.; Zuchelli, Hunter & Associates.; Billetdeaux, Neal.; BRW Inc.; R.W. Beck and Associates.; Pollack Design Associates.; Phillips, Sandra E.; Midwestern Consulting, Inc.
- Consultant Reports
  - Author unknown
    - The Huron River Valley study, circa 1960s (Box 1)
    - Research Park Service Center: a planned unit development, Undated (Box 1)
  - Ahern, Richard D.
    - A critique of the Central city high-rise and parking report, July 1965 (Box 1)
    - Thirty high: a survey of the potential of properties owned, optioned, or controlled by the Ann Arbor apartments trust, relative to their surrounding environs, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Alan M. Voorhees & Associates, in association with Economic Research Associates
    - Ann Arbor circulation study: prepared for city of Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1974-1975, June 1975 (Box 1)
      (See also Economic Research Associates)
  - Ann Arbor Municipal Airport Advisory Committee
    - A study of the Ann Arbor Municipal Airport, April 1962 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Mutual Housing Association
    - The Kemnitz Center, Senior Housing & Activities Center: proposal for redevelopment of The Ann Arbor Inn, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Tomorrow
    - Ann Arbor circulation study: a summary of the position of the Ann Arbor tomorrow Advisory Council on recommendations affecting the downtown, July 1, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Annual report, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Carpooling in downtown: background and feasibility for a carpool demonstration program in Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Downtown evening-use survey, by Fred Zeidman. March 1974 (Box 1)
    - Renovating upper stories: housing in the downtown, Ann Arbor, Michigan, April 1978 (Box 1)
      (See also Dykema, James, et al.)
      (See also Sullivan, Carol, and Griffin, Denise)
  - Arbor Main Associates
    - Arbor Main Place: a downtown anchor, circa 1985 (Box 1)
      (2 different versions)
    - Arbor Main Place: a multiple purpose facility, [1986] (Box 1)
    - Proposal for development on city-owned property at Packard and Main Streets, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Atwell-Hicks
    - Sanitary sewer study of the area bounded by Plymouth Road, Traver Creek, Dhu Varren Road and the divide easterly. June 1958 (Box 1)
      (See also Reid and Cool.)
  - Ayres, Lewis, Norris & May
    - A report on the city owned Huron River dams improvement and reconstruction recommendations. March 1969 (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Douglas, et al.
    - Hill Street: investigation of the planning process in Ann Arbor. April 1972 (Box 1)
  - Barton-Aschman Associates
    - Ann Arbor Urban Area transportation study: proposed bikeway system. May 1974 (Box 1)
    - Evaluation of alternative transit concepts [for Ann Arbor Transportation Authority], January 1979 (Box 1)
    - A transportation plan for the Ann Arbor Ypsilanti urbanized area, July 1975 (Box 1)
  - Beckett and Raeder Inc.
    - Domino's Farms: Domino's Pizza Incorporated, World Headquarters, proposed development plan, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Beckett Raeder Rankin
    - A Study for the Eastern Michigan University, Saint Joseph Mercy Hospital, Washtenaw Community College corridor, June 1979 (Box 1)
  - Billetdeaux, Neal, Brooke Farquhar, and Patricia Lang
    - North Main Street corridor: introduction and overview., February 16, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Brewer Engineering
    - Master plan report: Ann Arbor Municipal Airport--Ann Arbor, Michigan, September 1969 (Box 1)
  - BRH Mobility Services Company
    - Ann Arbor New-Tran basic project plan: report to Ann Arbor Transportation Authority. December 1973 (Box 1)
  - BRW, Inc.
    - Ann Arbor transportation plan, November 1990 (Box 1)
  - Building Officials Conference of America
    - A study of code enforcement in the city of Ann Arbor, Michigan, February 1969 (Box 1)
  - Byrd, David R.
    - The challenge of change. 1968 (Box 1)
  - Colvin-Robinson Associates (Box 1)
    (See Hellmuth, Obata & Kassabaum.)
  - Colvin, Robinson, Wright & Associates
    - City of Ann Arbor, Mich. Washington St.-Fourth Ave. parking structure, undated (Box 1)
  - Community Systems Foundation (Box 2)
    - A planning programming budgeting system for the city of Ann Arbor: two years progress in implementation, circa 1970 (Box 2)
  - Dykema, James, et al.
    - An Economic analysis of the Liberty Street corridor for Ann Arbor Tomorrow. December 1976 (Box 2)
  - Eberle M. Smith Associates, Inc.
    - Proposed parking deck, Ann Arbor, Michigan circa 1969 (Box 2)
  - Economic Research Associates
    - Analysis of future growth potential in the central circulation district in Ann Arbor, Michigan: prepared for Alan M. Voorhees and Associates. March 1974 (Box 2)
      (See also Alan M. Voorhees & Associates)
  - Eisenhower Community Council, and Johnson, William J.
    - Community values and thoroughfare planning, April 1973 (Box 2)
  - First Centrum Corporation
    - [Redevelopment proposal for the Ann Arbor Inn], 1993 (Box 2)
  - Ford Motor Company. Transportation Research and Planning Office
    - Interim report: Teltran facilities requirements: prepared for the Ann Arbor Transportation Authority, September 1973 (Box 2)
  - Griffin, Denise
    (See Sullivan, Carol)
  - Harland Bartholomew and Associates
    - A Traffic and parking analysis: the Ann Arbor thoroughfare plan in relation to University of Michigan Central Campus study: prepared for City of Ann Arbor, University of Michigan. June 1964 (Box 2)
  - Hellmuth, Obata & Kassabaum in association with Colvin-Robinson Associates
    - Master plan report for Washtenaw County, Michigan, criminal justice center, July 1975 (Box 2)
  - Herrmann Holman Meneghini Overhiser
    - Ann Arbor Transportation Authority downtown Ann Arbor transit center: a design study, phase II, September 1984 (Box 2)
  - Hobbs & Black Associates
    - Ashley Plaza, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Kojaian Building, Ann Arbor, Michigan, Undated (Box 2)
  - Hoffman, L. Wallace
    - From divorce court to family court: a survey of the Washtenaw County Circuit Court and the community attitudes toward the development of a marriage counseling service, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Hubbell, Roth and Clark, and Metro Engineers, Inc., and McNamee, Porter & Seeley
    - Summary report of draft I of the facility plan for the Huron Valley Wastewater Control System in Wayne and Oakland Counties, Michigan, and Draft facilities plan for wastewater management in the Ann Arbor-Ypsilanti areas of the Huron River Valley, Washtenaw County, Michigan, March 1976 (Box 2)
  - Huron-D&A Associates Partnership
    - Huron Plaza, Ann Arbor, Michigan, circa 1982 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, William J.
    (See Eisenhower Community Council)
  - Johnson & Anderson
    - Evaluation of load limits of three existing bridges, Ann Arbor, Michigan, circa 1965 (Box 2)
    - Feasibility study, Forest Avenue improvements, Ann Arbor, Michigan. July 1965 (Box 2)
    - Feasibility study, Forest Avenue improvements, Ann Arbor, Michigan., August 1965 (Box 2)
      (with December 1965 supplement)
    - Feasibility study, Forest Avenue improvements, Ann Arbor, Michigan. September 1965 (Box 2)
    - Feasibility study, Fuller Road improvements and grade separation replacement of Fuller Road over Consolidated Rail Corp, January 1978 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Johnson & Roy
    - Addenda to the final report recommendations central city high-rise and parking, August 1965 (Box 2)
    - Final report recommendations: report on CBD high-rise development and parking, July 1965 (Box 2)
    - Garden Homes Subdivision study: a plan to guide future physical development, August 1971 (Box 2)
    - Kerrytown/Farmers' Market neighborhood study, January 1987. (Box 2)
      (See also McNamee, Porter & Seeley)
  - Jones & Henry Engineers
    - A Washtenaw County plan for the management of solid waste: revised plan. February 1975 (Box 2)
  - Jones & Henry Engineers, and Sanders & Thomas
    - Washtenaw County, Michigan, plan for the management of solid waste: final report. June 1982 (Box 2)
  - Kaplan Associates
    - Arbor Main Place development project, Ann Arbor, Michigan, Undated (Box 2)
  - McNamee, Porter & Seeley
    - Pollution control plan for the Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti service areas, August 1969 (Box 2)
    - Sanitary sewerage study for the north and west sides of the city for Ann Arbor, Michigan, March 1969 (Box 2)
      (See also Hubbell, Roth and Clark)
  - McNamee, Porter & Seeley, and Johnson, Johnson & Roy
    - Allen's Creek Drain: analysis & preliminary alternatives for relief: interim report prepared for the Washtenaw County Drain Commission, February 1974 (Box 2)
  - Metro Engineers, Inc.
    (See Hubbell, Roth and Clark)
  - Midwestern Consulting
    - Final design recommendations for the Traver Creek Chapter 20 Drain. July 1972 (Box 3)
    - Plymouth mall, circa 1972 (Box 3)
    - Revised final design recommendations for Traver Creek Chapter 20 Drain, city of Ann Arbor, January 1974 (Box 3)
    - Sanitary sewer study: covering a portion of Garden Homes Subdivision for the City of Ann Arbor, Ann Arbor Township, September 1968 (Box 3)
    - Traver Lakes, Ann Arbor, Michigan: a planned community in concept, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Palmer, John S.
    - Project task recommendations for alternative five of the interim report I dated February 1974 a program for action, November 1974 (Box 3)
  - Pelz, Donald C., et al.
    - Survey on Ann Arbor transportation--Summer 1973 sponsored by planning Department, Traffic Engineering and Transportation Department, City of Ann Arbor, Michigan, November 1973 (Box 3)
  - Phillips, Sandra E.
    - An independent feasibility study of the Ann Arbor Airport. February 1993 (Box 3)
  - Pollack Design Associates
    - The Ann Arbor Depot: development alternatives, April 1980 (Box 3)
    - The Ann Arbor Depot: a first phase investigation of location alternatives for rail passenger facilities, November 1979 (Box 3)
    - Master plan for pedestrian improvements, Downtown Development Authority district, Ann Arbor, Michigan: final draft for review and comment, January 1987 (Box 3)
  - Preservation Urban Design
    - Ann Arbor downtown facade study. January 1976 (Box 3)
    - Westside neighborhood plan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, April 1977 (Box 3)
  - Quinn, Robert P.
    - Survey of citizen satisfaction in Ann Arbor, August 1977 (Box 3)
  - R. Gordon Mathews and Associates
    (See Midwestern Consulting, Inc.)
  - R.W. Beck and Associates
    - Factors affecting the success of residential and commercial recycling programs: mandatory recycling ordinance and variable rate fee structures (Working paper no. 1), November 1989 (Box 3)
  - Ralph M. Parsons Company
    (See TransPlan, Inc.)
  - Regional Research Associates, Inc.
    - Growth and development of the city of Ann Arbor, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Reid, Lloyd B.
    - Measures for relieving Ann Arbor street traffic conditions. October 1956. (Box 3)
    - Measures for relieving Ann Arbor street traffic conditions: statistical appendix, circa 1956 (Box 3)
  - Reid and Cool
    - Road improvements required to serve traffic at a Saline Road, I-94 shopping center, Ann Arbor, Michigan, May 1966 (Box 3)
    - Traffic study, I-94 penetrator routes, Ann Arbor, Michigan, April 1969 (Box 3)
  - Reid and Cool, and Atwell-Hicks
    - Report, I-94 penetrator traffic study, downtown bypass study for the city of Ann Arbor, Michigan, June 1966 (Box 3)
  - Residents Against Packard Platt Plaza
    - Analysis of proposed Packard Platt Plaza development, [1972 ?] (Box 3)
  - Rossetti Associates
    (See Huron-D&A Associates Partnership)
  - Sanders & Thomas. (Box 3)
    (See Jones & Henry Engineers)
  - Sanzenbacher, Miller & Brigham
    - Report of engineering studies for the proposed improvement of Newport Road Miller Avenue to city limits, city of Ann Arbor, Michigan, circa 1958 (Box 3)
  - Schimpeler-Corradino Associates
    - Huron Valley corridor study: final report, July 1978 (Box 3)
    - Huron Valley corridor study: sketch planning analysis of alternatives, April 1977 (Box 3)
    - Huron Valley corridor study: summary detailed planning analysis of alternatives, October 1977 (Box 3)
    - Potential transportation improvement solutions for the Huron Valley Corridor, November 1976 (Box 3)
  - Schneider Group
    - Courtyards of The Seasons: a home ownership development 1988 (Box 3)
    - Response to request for proposal for the development of city-owned property at Packard and Main Streets, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Sullivan, Carol, and Griffin, Denise
    - Downtown parking: the situation, the need, the prospects. For Ann Arbor Tomorrow, July 1976 (Box 3)
  - Technical Network Inc.
    - A Report on population and housing based on the 1960-1970-1980 federal census: Ann Arbor, Michigan: prepared for Arbor Main Place proposed development, July 1984 (Box 3)
  - TransPlan, Inc.
    - Master plan for Ann Arbor Airport: phase I., circa 1975 (Box 3)
  - W.C. Gilman & Co.
    - City of Ann Arbor, Michigan, technical transit study, June 1969 (Box 3)
  - Wayne C. Johnson & Associates
    - Economic impact study, Arbor Main proposed development: 180 apartment unites, 13,185 square feet office, 10,497 square feet commercial, and a 304-car parking structure, circa 1984 (Box 3)
  - Zeidman, Fred
    (See Ann Arbor Tomorrow)
  - Zuchelli, Hunter & Associates
    - Assessment and evaluation of downtown redevelopment opportunities, Ann Arbor, Michigan: prepared for the City of Ann Arbor, Michigan, the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority. June 1984 (Box 3)